<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Earthquakes on </title>
    <link>/tags/earthquakes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Earthquakes on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/earthquakes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to Earthquakes</title>
      <link>/learningunits/1_primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learningunits/1_primer/</guid>
      <description>To start with, here is a famous recording to illustrate the kinds of sounds we actually hear during an earthquake, from the 1976 Friuli earthquake in Italy:   A boy was transferring his Pink Floyd record to cassette by holding a microphone up to the speaker connected to the turntable. When the first wave arrived, the P-wave (or compressional wave), the needle jumped. Then the second, larger set of waves arrived, the S-waves (or shear waves).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tectonic Earthquakes: Patterns in space and time</title>
      <link>/learningunits/2_tectoniceqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learningunits/2_tectoniceqs/</guid>
      <description>First, plate motions (plate tectonics) on Earth is driven by the convection of the deep interior, or mantle. Here&amp;rsquo;s a movie of convection over two billion years, BILLION!, sped up to play in 36 seconds:
  If we slow way down, we can look at and hear something like what those plates sound like as they grind past each other and cause earthquakes. To do so, we animate the data with sound, using these rules to generate these movies of ``earthquake catalogs&amp;rdquo;, or lists of earthquakes by location, date, magnitude, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volcanoes and Earthquakes</title>
      <link>/learningunits/3_volcanoesandeqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learningunits/3_volcanoesandeqs/</guid>
      <description>Every volcano has a wide range of processes going on inside that generate seismic waves. Some of these are &amp;lsquo;normal&amp;rsquo; earthquakes, some are tremors associated with magma moving around in its plumbing. We will build more movies of other volcanoes soon, but for now, here is our rough draft of catalogs from the Kilauea eruption of 2018. Listen for the cyclic patterns in the following movie. We have never seen this kind of pattern in an eruption, and are working to understand how this happens:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-induced earthquakes and Energy</title>
      <link>/learningunits/4_humaninducedeqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learningunits/4_humaninducedeqs/</guid>
      <description>In some cases, hydrocarbon and geothermal heat extraction processes cause earthquakes. Listening to various settings where these occur clearly conveys the differences between human-induced and tectonic earthquakes, and raises many interesting societal questions.
Wastewater from shale gas extraction by &amp;ldquo;fracking&amp;rdquo; is toxic enough that most states will not allow it to be stored or disposed of in-state. Oklahoma and Ohio permitted wastewater to be injected deep in the ground. The injection occurs at high pressure so that the fluid flow deep into some deep layer in the crust and will stay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geysers and Volcanoes: Scaling by Analogy</title>
      <link>/learningunits/5_geysers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learningunits/5_geysers/</guid>
      <description>Geysers are hydrothermal features that episodically erupt liquid and vapor. The eruptions that we see at the surface are the culmination of a complex series of processes below the ground hidden from direct observation. But that doesn’t mean they are hidden entirely; we can monitor them with various sensors to record different aspects of the system. For example, a tilt meter can measure the inflation of the ground due to pressure build up before an eruption, and a seismometer can measure hydrothermal ‘tremor’, which tells us about the bubbling of the hot liquid.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>